Let's look at the feedforward part first.
我们先来看前馈的部分
To make our computations easier,
为了简化计算
let's decide to have n inputs,
我们取 n 个输入
three neurons in a single hidden layer, and two outputs.
一个包含三个神经元的隐藏层 以及两个输出
By the way in practice,
顺便提一句 在现实中
we can have thousands of neurons in a single hidden layer.
一个隐藏层可以有数千个神经元
We will use W1 as the set of weights from X to
我们用 W1 来表示 x 与 h 之间的权重集合
H and W2 as the set of weights from H to Y.
用 W2 来表示 h 与 y 之间的权重集合
Since we have only one hidden layer,
由于我们只有一个隐藏层
we will have only two steps in each feedforward cycle.
所以每个前馈循环只有两步
Step one, will be finding H from a given input and a set of weights W1.
第一步 借助权重集合 W1 来求与给定输入对应的 h
And step two, will be finding the output Y from
第二步 借助权重集合 W2
the calculated H and the set of weights W2.
求得与上一步得到的 h 对应的输出 y
You will find that other than the use of non-linear activation functions,
你会发现 除了用非线性激活函数外
all of the calculations involve linear combinations of inputs and weights,
所有计算都涉及输入与权重的线性组合
or in other words, we will use matrix multiplications.
换句话说 都会用到矩阵乘法
Let's start with step number one,
我们先讲第一步
finding H. Notice that,
求 h
if we have more than one neuron in the hidden layer which is usually the case,
注意 如果隐藏层神经元不止一个 其实神经元数目通常都不止一个
H is actually a vector.
那 h 就是一个向量
We will have our initial inputs X,
我们会取初始输入 x
X is also a vector.
x 也是一个向量
And we want to find the values of the hidden neurons
来求隐藏神经元的值 h
H. Each input is connected to each neuron in the hidden layer.
每个输入会与隐藏层的各神经元相连
For simplicity, we will use
为了叙述方便
the following indices W11 connects X1 to H1,
我们会用以下指称 W11 连接 x1 和 h1
W13 connects X1 to H3,
W13 连接 x1 和 h3
W21 connects X2 to H1,
W21 连接 x2 和 h1
Wn3 connects Xn to H3 and so on.
Wn3 连接 xn 和 h3 以此类推
The vector of the inputs X1, X to the second,
把输入向量 x1、x2
all the way up to Xn is multiplied by
一直到 xn
the weight matrix W1 to give us the hidden neurons.
与权重矩阵 W1 相乘 从而得出隐藏神经元
So, each vector H equals vector X multiplied by the weight matrix W1.
所以 每个向量 h 都等于向量 x 乘以权重矩阵 W1 的值
In this case, we have a weight matrix with N rows,
此时 我们的权重矩阵有 n 行
as we have N inputs,
因为我们有 n 个输入
and three columns as we have three neurons in the hidden layer.
3 列 因为隐藏层有三个神经元
If you multiply the input vector by the weight matrix,
如果让输入向量乘以权重矩阵
you will have a simple linear combination for each neuron in
隐藏层的各神经元就会得到一个简单的线性组合
the hidden layer giving us vector H. So for example,
由此可求得向量 h
H to the first will be X1 times W11
举个例子 h1 就会等于 x1 * W11
plus X2 times W21, and so on.
+ x2 * W21… 以此类推
But we are not done with calculating the hidden layer yet.
但至此隐藏层的计算尚未结束
Notice the prime symbol I've been using?
注意到这里的 “ ’ ” 符号了吗？
I used it to remind us that we are not done with finding H yet.
指的就是我们还没求得 h
We're almost there, but not quite yet.
就快了 但还差一点
To make sure that the values of H do not explode or increase too much in size,
为了防止 h 的值爆炸或涨幅过多
we need to use an activation function.
我们需要使用激活函数